# **Eric Kirberger**

102 Crest Court Milford, PA 18337 Phone: 908-229-0170

Email: erickirberger@gmail.com

LinkedIn: [LinkedIn](https://linkedin.com/in/eric-kirberger/)

GitHub: [GitHub](https://github.com/ekirbs)

Portfolio: [Portfolio](https://ekirbs.github.io/react-portfolio/)

## Summary

Dedicated Full-Stack Java Developer with experience in design, development, and Agile methodologies like SCRUM, Test-Driven Development (TDD), Incremental and Iteration methodology, and Testing using Software Development Life Cycle. Experienced in Development, Testing, and Deployment of enterprise applications on Windows, Linux, and UNIX platforms using IDEs such as Eclipse, VSCode, and IntelliJ14.X/15.X.

# **Technical Skills**

# Back-End Development

- Languages: Java
- Frameworks & Libraries: Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Batch, Spring Eureka, Spring ORM, Lombok
- Build & Dependency Management: Maven, NodeJS
- APIs & Tools: Apollo Server, Express.js, Axios

# Front-End Development

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS
- Frameworks & Libraries: React.js, Vue.js, Angular, jQuery
- Styling Frameworks: Material UI, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize

# Database Management

- SQL: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize
- NoSQL: MongoDB, Mongoose

### Cloud & Deployment

- Platforms & Services: AWS (CloudFormation, S3, ECR, ECS, RDS, SecretsManager, Simple Email Service, VPC, Load Balancers), Firebase/Firestore, Heroku
- Containers & Orchestration: Docker, ECS

### DevOps & CI/CD

- Tools: Jenkins, SonarQube, Jacoco
- CI/CD Configuration & Scripting: Jenkinsfiles (Groovy), YAML
- Version Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab, GitBash

## **API & Documentation Tools**

API Testing & Documentation: Swagger, Insomnia, GraphQL

### Workflow & Project Management

• Tools: Jira, Confluence

#### **Testing & Quality Assurance**

Frameworks & Libraries: JUnit(Java/Spring Boot), Mockito(Java/Spring Boot), Jest(React), Jasmine(Angular)

# **Featured Projects**

## Financial Banking Application – Data Generation and Batch Services

Mar 2023 - Present

GitLab: https://git1.smoothstack.com/cohorts/2023/2023 12 11 java/organizations/the-ledger-legends

A Spring Batch microservice that performs data generation and data filtering. Each batch job can filter and parse log files to receive critical information for the bank to make effective, analytical based decisions.

- Designed a batch job in Spring Batch to analyze and enrich data from 24-million-line CSV files.
- Leveraged multi-threading to boost Batch jobs efficiently.
- Securely transmitted data across networks.

#### **Environment:**

Java - Spring Boot, Spring Batch | SQL - PostgreSQL | TypeScript - Angular | Jasmine | REST APIs | Docker | CI/CD - Jenkins | AWS Services

# **Financial Banking Application**

Dec 2023 - Present

GitLab: https://git1.smoothstack.com/cohorts/2023/2023 12 11 java/organizations/the-ledger-legends

A banking application with both a public member portal and an administration portal. Utilizes multiple core microservices that are used to comprehensively execute main application functionalities such as member registration, executing credit/debit card transactions, account balance management, member management, and loan management.

- Produced a comprehensive RESTful microservice architecture.
- Utilized Spring framework (core | IoC | Web | Security).
- Efficiently leveraged Amazon Web Services (AWS) for a high availability, on demand, cloud delivery solution.
- Properly managed data confidentiality and integrity both at rest and in transit.
- Enabled and managed the accurate and reliable transmission of data between the data layer and the presentation layer using DAOs and DTOs.
- Ensured robust continuous delivery through a Jenkins managed CI/CD pipeline.

# **Environment:**

Java – Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Data JPA over Hibernate | Junit | SQL – PostgreSQL | JavaScript – React.js | Jest | Typescript – Angular | Jasmine | HTML | CSS | Material UI | REST APIs | Docker | CI/CD – Jenkins | AWS – RDS, ECS, S3, CloudFormation | Agile Framework

Task Sandwich Feb 2023

GitHub: https://github.com/sam-lerner/task-sandwich

A MERN project-management platform with built-in rewards system.

- Developed clean front-end using React.js, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap for intuitive, user-friendly experience.
- Implemented mobile-first responsive web design.
- Utilized Node.js and React.js components to interact with MongoDB, Apollo Server, and GraphQL for seamless database operations.

### **Environment:**

JavaScript - React.js | NoSQL - MongoDB | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | REST APIs | Heroku

# **Professional Experience**

### Full-Stack Java Engineer - Associate

Milford, PA

Smoothstack Inc. Dec 2023 – Present

- Architected and deployed scalable microservices using Java and Spring Boot, enhancing the performance and reliability of banking operations while ensuring seamless integration with third-party APIs.
- Collaborated in an Agile SCRUM environment to deliver secure, high-performance financial services, leveraging Angular for dynamic front-end development and PostgreSQL for optimized backend data management.
- Spearheaded the design and implementation of batch processing workflows with Spring Batch, automating high-volume data transactions and improving system efficiency for mission-critical banking functions.

# Report Administrator, QA/QC Administrator

Mine Hill, NJ

LEW Environmental Services

March 2021 – June 2022

- Audited complex technical and legal reports for accuracy and consistency.
- Communicated effectively with team and clients to meet project requirements.
- Trained and supervised new employees, fostering a skilled workforce.

### Founder, Head Instructor

Stirling, NJ

Central Heights Fencing Club

June 2010 - April 2020

- Managed fencing schedules for 2 teams, adapting as needed.
- Developed innovative lesson plans to enhance student engagement.
- Created a supportive environment, boosting participation.

# Teacher

Morris County, NJ

September 2012 – April 2020

- Long Hill Township School District
  - Taught core subjects to diverse student groups, adapting methods to student needs.
  - Enhanced lessons with creative approaches, sparking student interest.
  - Developed individualized plans for students with varying learning levels.

# **Education**

# Rutgers State University Full Stack Web Development Program

New Brunswick, NJ

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

- Proficiency in React, Handlebars, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.
- Database development using MongoDB and MySQL.
- Server building with Express.js and Apollo/GraphQL.
- Equipped with skills for effective project management in dynamic development environments.

### **Rutgers State University**

New Brunswick, NJ

Bachelor's Degree in Philosophy w. minor in History